[{"question":"Which of the following is not a reserved word in JavaScript?","options":["interface","throws","short","program"],"correct_answer":"program","id":"071e2498-3574-4fc3-91bd-676c84cdcfdb"},{"question":"What is the correct JavaScript syntax to change the content of the following HTML element: <p id='demo'>This is a demonstration.</p>?","options":["document.getElementByName('p').innerHTML = 'Hello World!';","document.getElementById('demo').innerHTML = 'Hello World!';","#demo.innerHTML = 'Hello World!';","document.getElementsById('demo')[0].innerText = 'Hello World!';"],"correct_answer":"document.getElementById('demo').innerHTML = 'Hello World!';","id":"78637146-ed0e-4068-863e-43dc70589078"},{"question":"Which of the following function of String object extracts a section of a string and returns a new string?","options":["slice()","split()","replace()","search()"],"correct_answer":"slice()","id":"ecbfe73c-feb1-4d63-ad07-c87512de5a60"},{"question":"Which built-in method returns the length of the string?","options":["length()","size()","index()","None of the above."],"correct_answer":"None of the above.","id":"1676ada5-e909-4a67-9c7a-347da8ecd64b"},{"question":"Which of the following will write the message 'Hello DataFlair!' in an alert box?","options":["alertBox('Hello DataFlair!');","msgAlert('Hello DataFlair!');","msg('Hello DataFlair!');","alert('Hello DataFlair!');"],"correct_answer":"alert('Hello DataFlair!');","id":"30ba9b6c-e2a5-4e05-bf0e-c309a7077f91"},{"question":"How do you initialize an array in JavaScript?","options":["let arr = (1,2,3);","let arr = [1,2,3];","let arr = {1,2,3};","let arr = <1,2,3>;"],"correct_answer":"let arr = [1,2,3];","id":"a24dd247-bdd6-4d52-8704-3416e1c94a05"},{"question":"What will the following code return? Boolean(10 > 9)","options":["NaN","false","true","undefined"],"correct_answer":"true","id":"a30acd7d-bca3-497f-a71a-88c08bb56272"},{"question":"Which method of an Array object adds and/or removes elements from an array?","options":["toSource()","sort()","splice()","unshift()"],"correct_answer":"splice()","id":"a05329bf-3e80-45bd-a369-d9ea897fda12"},{"question":"Which of the following is not a JavaScript framework or library?","options":["Python","React","Angular","Vue"],"correct_answer":"Python","id":"2c1f87bb-610f-45a9-906d-e45930111917"},{"question":"What is the correct way to create a JavaScript array?","options":["let colors = 1 = ('red'), 2 = ('green'), 3 = ('blue');","let colors = (1:'red', 2:'green', 3:'blue');","let colors = 'red','green','blue';","let colors = ['red', 'green', 'blue'];"],"correct_answer":"let colors = ['red', 'green', 'blue'];","id":"8c807077-27a5-4053-93fc-2b9ce9e3b5ed"},{"question":"Which of the following is the correct syntax to redirect a URL using JavaScript?","options":["window.location = 'http://www.example.com';","document.location = 'http://www.example.com';","browser.redirect('http://www.example.com');","navigator.location = 'http://www.example.com';"],"correct_answer":"window.location = 'http://www.example.com';","id":"3fd47321-83f7-4e95-a7b8-635aca2d9383"},{"question":"Which built-in method combines the text of two strings and returns a new string?","options":["append()","concat()","attach()","combine()"],"correct_answer":"concat()","id":"074fa052-1948-4489-ade1-781afa70eee4"},{"question":"Which of the following function of Array object returns the last (greatest) index of an element within the array equal to the specified value, or -1 if none is found?","options":["indexOf()","join()","lastIndexOf()","map()"],"correct_answer":"lastIndexOf()","id":"96a9bde5-87e2-4633-9204-6a154dbb37fd"},{"question":"Which of the following function of String object returns the character at the specified index?","options":["charAt()","charCodeAt()","concat()","indexOf()"],"correct_answer":"charAt()","id":"b8d2ab02-777a-43aa-a43e-c31448230b46"},{"question":"Which of the following function of Array object applies a function simultaneously against two values of the array (from left-to-right) as to reduce it to a single value?","options":["pop()","push()","reduce()","reduceRight()"],"correct_answer":"reduce()","id":"340ea23b-8661-42d0-9e60-1d55d4c71f45"},{"question":"Which statement is used to test for a specific condition in JavaScript?","options":["switch","if","loop","debug"],"correct_answer":"if","id":"fc8e994d-72cc-47c8-959f-d4a96ae25537"},{"question":"How would you write 'Hello World' in an alert box?","options":["alert('Hello World');","msgBox('Hello World');","alertBox('Hello World');","msg('Hello World');"],"correct_answer":"alert('Hello World');","id":"a3dd3610-9dd4-4eae-be23-41b95685f11a"},{"question":"What is the JavaScript syntax for getting an element with the id 'demo'?","options":["document.getElement('demo');","document.getElementById('demo');","document.pickElement('demo');","document.querySelector('#demo');"],"correct_answer":"document.getElementById('demo');","id":"944329f3-72ba-4312-ab78-6ea95ad1077a"},{"question":"How can you add a comment in JavaScript?","options":["//This is a comment","/*This is a comment*/","<!--This is a comment-->","Both option 1 and 2"],"correct_answer":"Both option 1 and 2","id":"8a7af450-9e0f-4975-818d-99e2ae13fdb9"},{"question":"Which global function can be used to parse a string to an integer?","options":["toNumber()","toInt()","parseFloat()","parseInt()"],"correct_answer":"parseInt()","id":"4fd8e935-60fc-4fb5-aaef-60e9504817ed"},{"question":"Which of the following is a server-side JavaScript environment?","options":["React","JQuery","Node.js","TypeScript"],"correct_answer":"Node.js","id":"6a12885d-037a-466f-bae0-8df1dc2fd105"},{"question":"What will the following code output? `console.log(typeof null);`","options":["undefined","null","object","number"],"correct_answer":"object","id":"8b44789e-bf07-46c2-b52a-8a9fb74ed298"},{"question":"Which of the following is true about `==` in JavaScript?","options":["It compares values and types.","It compares only values.","It compares only references.","It compares nothing."],"correct_answer":"It compares only values.","id":"b6d00cb3-efeb-433a-a69a-6b732c9c3992"},{"question":"What method can be used to encode a URL in JavaScript?","options":["urlEncode()","encodeURI()","encodeURIComponent()","Both option 2 and 3"],"correct_answer":"Both option 2 and 3","id":"3a348451-3ab2-449b-bcbe-907a3e1f3ce5"},{"question":"Which event fires whenever a control loses focus?","options":["onblur","onfocus","onformchange","onforminput"],"correct_answer":"onblur","id":"46a5d5be-b7b0-497c-be5e-88fd987af7fc"},{"question":"What is the purpose of the JavaScript `Array.prototype.map()` function?","options":["It loops through each item in an array.","It tests whether at least one element in the array passes the test implemented by the provided function.","It creates a new array with the results of calling a function for every array element.","It merges two or more arrays."],"correct_answer":"It creates a new array with the results of calling a function for every array element.","id":"f95ec153-9346-4ebc-bd2c-742bf96dc6e9"},{"question":"Which of the following will correctly create a JavaScript object?","options":["let obj = { key: 'value' };","let obj = (key: 'value');","let obj = [key: 'value'];","let obj = <key: 'value'>;"],"correct_answer":"let obj = { key: 'value' };","id":"1d75ec46-6dd3-497d-97d0-135700476863"},{"question":"In JavaScript, which of the following is NOT a truthy value?","options":["'0'","[]","NaN","'false'"],"correct_answer":"NaN","id":"58e2d27c-f5cf-4414-97ca-37e1892d8f1e"},{"question":"What does the `this` keyword refer to inside a JavaScript function?","options":["The function itself","The object that the function is a method of","The global object (like window in browsers)","It varies depending on how the function is called"],"correct_answer":"It varies depending on how the function is called","id":"3808a72d-1946-432c-a393-ccb2e13c1d9e"},{"question":"Which HTML attribute is used to include an external JavaScript file?","options":["link","import","include","src"],"correct_answer":"src","id":"19abaa32-ba4e-4325-80b1-1b6bb8c90dd4"},{"question":"Which of the following is the correct way to comment out multiple lines in JavaScript?","options":["// This comment style only","/* This comment style */","<!-- This comment style -->","-- This comment style --"],"correct_answer":"/* This comment style */","id":"a67bbe7b-a24e-41bf-b480-62aebb8eea97"},{"question":"Which JavaScript label catches all the values, except for the ones specified?","options":["catch","label","try","default"],"correct_answer":"default","id":"22c5bf78-dfbd-45cf-8064-5fa4621e9a23"},{"question":"Which is the correct JavaScript syntax to change the HTML content of the following code? `<p id='test'>Hello World!</p>`","options":["document.getElement('test').innerHTML = 'Hello Universe!';","document.getElementById('test').innerText = 'Hello Universe!';","document.pickElement('test').innerHTML = 'Hello Universe!';","#test.innerHTML = 'Hello Universe!';"],"correct_answer":"document.getElementById('test').innerText = 'Hello Universe!';","id":"7ac4ae71-1337-43f4-9300-b528a2b5f54d"},{"question":"Inside which HTML element do we put the JavaScript?","options":["<javascript>","<scripting>","<js>","<script>"],"correct_answer":"<script>","id":"7aebfbe5-c2cf-492f-9199-3f60b538e642"},{"question":"Which event occurs when the user clicks on an HTML element?","options":["onchange","onmouseover","onclick","onmouseclick"],"correct_answer":"onclick","id":"7d7e54d9-d8a1-4e16-b9a3-814ab56f17e2"},{"question":"How do you write an IF statement in JavaScript?","options":["if i == 5 then","if (i == 5)","if i = 5","if i = 5 then"],"correct_answer":"if (i == 5)","id":"48960c91-a654-47a1-b8e4-40b644bd15d8"},{"question":"How can you add a new property to an existing object?","options":["obj.add('newProp', 'value');","obj.newProp = 'value';","obj('newProp') = 'value';","obj.addValue('newProp', 'value');"],"correct_answer":"obj.newProp = 'value';","id":"6108ab05-0742-40d9-be07-0320eb1ae808"},{"question":"How do you find the number with the highest value of x and y?","options":["Math.ceil(x, y);","Math.highest(x, y);","Math.max(x, y);","top(x, y);"],"correct_answer":"Math.max(x, y);","id":"04f3bb99-a2f1-46a4-9fb7-9f1ad3f9c2ec"},{"question":"Which method can determine if a string ends with a specified substring?","options":["endsWith()","lastSubstring()","tail()","final()"],"correct_answer":"endsWith()","id":"f86bda9a-cd42-4d8f-b95d-9a8a2dad322b"},{"question":"Which method can be used to encode a JSON object to a string?","options":["JSON.parse()","JSON.stringify()","JSON.encode()","JSON.translate()"],"correct_answer":"JSON.stringify()","id":"9fe10da2-d985-44f0-80ac-27e3c89589b8"},{"id":"4ccb9ce1-de83-440a-8383-5a5fbf289ec5","options":["New Abstract Number","No Available Number","None of the Above","Not a Number"],"correct_answer":"Not a Number"}]